<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Not Null</title>
    <description>Passionate software developer, cloud and devops enthusiast.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 17:50:07 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 17:50:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three years of therapy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, I started seeing a therapist. My life was falling apart back then, and I wasn’t able to handle it.
I barely recognize the person I was at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often share it with people around me how life changing these 3 years have been for me. And I openly tell everyone to go and do
therapy themselves, even if they think they don’t need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest differences I notice now, is that I’m actually able to notice when something in my life bothers me not for what it
is, but for what it triggers in me. Seeing this clearly helps me know when I’m reacting out of proportions to something in the present,
because of something in the past. This happens more often than I could have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therapy also helped me see that the way I live my life has mostly not changed throughout time. I have moved a lot, and although I hated
it as a kid, I continued on doing it even after I had a choice on the matter. I have also left people behind a lot. Moving so much tends
to make that natural, and so I kept on doing it throughout my adult life.
At first, I thought this was a way to reinvent myself. It seemed I was able to leave who I was behind and start fresh on every move.
If this seems like an overly romanticized view of it, it’s because it is. Burying my past didn’t quite work. It was just a way of
building walls around myself. Just another armor. I’m not fighting anymore, but kept the armor on, just in case I guess. Just in case
life would decide to fuck me over again. And oh it has. More than once, more than twice. But the last time everything went upside down,
I was tired of the weight of armor, tired of not letting people come close, past my walls. Therapy has helped me understand why I built
these mechanisms of defense, and to tear them down one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not done, not even close. This kind of work is never done. But I’m doing a lot better, and I feel proud of my journey. Well, of
parts of it at least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/personal/2020/12/13/three-years-of-therapy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/personal/2020/12/13/three-years-of-therapy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
